(
"ai_sub_version": "3.5.2",
"generated_at": "2026-09-18T23:11:10.819204",
"lyrics_prompt_version": 9,
"subtitles_prompt_version": 18,
"complete": true,
"max_retries_exceeded": false,
"any_pending": false,
"settings": (
"ai": (
"model": null,
"model_subtitles": "google-gla:gemini-3.5-flash",
"model_lyrics": "google-gla:gemini-3.5-flash-lite",
"rpm": 4,
"tpm": 250000,
"google": (
"file_cache_ttl": 10,
"use_files_api": true,
"max_storage_gb": 18.0
),
"search": (
"qps": 0.3,
"max_length": 4096,
"web_search_tool": "langsearch",
"timeout": 60.0,
"retries": 3,
"min_wait_seconds": 1.0,
"max_wait_seconds": 10.0,
"multiplier": 2.0
),
"validation_buffer_ms": 2000,
"verification_gap_seconds": 60,
"gap_verification_retries": 1,
"gap_verification_ignore_start": true,
"gap_verification_ignore_end": true
),
"split": (
"max_seconds": 300,
"re_encode": (
"enabled": false,
"fps": 1.0,
"height": 360,
"bitrate_kb": 35,
"threshold_mb": 20,
"duration_tolerance_ms": 100,
"encoder": null
),
"start_offset_min": 0
"thread": (
"uploads": 4,
"re_encode": 2,
"lyrics": 4,
"subtitles": 4
),
"retry": (
"per_run": 5,
"max_runs": 3,
"multiplier": 2.0,
"min_wait_seconds": 30.0,
"max_wait_seconds": 300
),
"log": (
"level": "info",
"timestamps": true,
"scrub": false,
"progress_bars": true,
"progress_bar_width": 80,
"progress_bar_refresh_seconds": 1.0
)
Reversible 風真いろは生誕LIVE 2025
Reversible: Kazama Iroha Birthday LIVE 2025
皆さん！
Everyone!
風真いろは生誕LIVE2025、
Welcome to Kazama Iroha Birthday LIVE 2025!
来てくださいましてありがとうございます！
Thank you so much for coming!
全力で楽しんでいってくださいね！
Please enjoy yourselves to the very fullest!
想像なんてしてなかった
I never could have imagined this
現状 君もそう思った？
The present state... did you think so too?
最高で止まらないように
So we don't stop at our best,
更新したい
I want to keep updating it.
叶えたい夢まであとどれくらい？
How much further until the dream I want to fulfill?
誰も行ったことがない場所へ
To a place where no one has ever been before,
辿り着くまでは僕ら止まらない
until we reach it, we won't stop.
多分しんどいけど どうかよろしくね
It might be tough, but please look after me.
ねえねえ たまにメーデー
Hey, hey, sometimes it's a mayday,
僕だけじゃ作れないもの
something I can't create all on my own.
僕とか君とかあたしとか
Whether it's me, you, or myself,
恋とか愛とかまとめて全部
romance or love, bringing it all together...
君を置いてどこかに行っちゃうとか
Leaving you behind to go somewhere else...
ありえないよ
That's just impossible!
君がくれた音に 弾けた火花に
To the sound you gave me, to the bursting spark...
初めましてから ずっと恋しちゃってるんだよ
Ever since we first met, I've been in love with you.
君のいない未来 考えらんないよ
I can't even imagine a future without you.
これから先も二人がいいじゃん
From now on too, it's best if we're together, right?
一途になるほど 逃げ出すものさよ
The more single-minded you get, the more it slips away.
散々な僕のこと 呼んでくれてありがとう
Thank you for calling out to a disaster like me.
君のいない未来 考えらんないよ
I can't even imagine a future without you.
これから先も二人で そう、それがいいじゃん
From now on too, the two of us... Yes, that's best, right?
妄想 膨らんでくストーリー
Delusions, a swelling story,
感傷 やけに凹んじゃって
Sentimentality, feeling awfully down,
代償 求めすぎは嫌よ
Compensation, I hate demanding too much.
終わんない愛の連鎖 どうでしょう
How about an endless chain of love?
ねえねえ おいでメーデー
Hey, hey, come here, mayday,
僕が君にできること
what I can do for you...
まだまだまだまだあるけど
There's still so, so, so, so much more...
聴かせたいからじゃないんだ
It's not because I want you to listen to it,
君の「愛」がいつも勝っちゃうこと
it's because your "love" always wins.
許さないよ
I won't forgive you!
おーいえい
Oh yeah!
君以外はヤダ
Anyone but you is a no-no!
わがままはただ
My selfish wish is just...
「変わらないときめき」を提供しちゃうのはバカ？
...is it foolish of me to provide you with "unchanging excitement"?
君がくれた音に 弾けた火花に
With the sound you gave me, and the sparks that flew,
はじめましてから ずっと恋しちゃってるんだよ
I've been in love with you ever since we first met.
君のいない未来 考えられないよ
I can't imagine a future without you!
これから先も二人がいいじゃん
It's better if we're together from now on, right?
道連れになるほど 逃げたくもなったよ
At times I wanted to escape so much that I'd drag you with me.
散々な僕のこと 呼んでくれてありがとう
Thank you for calling out to a miserable person like me.
君のいない未来 考えられないよ
I can't imagine a future without you!
これから先も二人で そう、それがいいじゃん
It's better if we're together from now on, yes, that's just perfect!
はい！というわけで、皆の衆！こんいろはでござるー！
Yes! So, everyone! Kon-Iroha-de-gozaru!
ホロライブ6期生、つよつよかっこいいござるサムライ、風真いろはでござるー！
Hololive 6th Gen, the super-strong, cool gozaru samurai, Kazama Iroha here!
はい！今年の誕生日1発目は、DECO*27さんの愛言葉シリーズ、4！愛言葉Ⅳを歌って踊らせていただきましたー！
Yes! For the first song of this year's birthday celebration, I sang and danced to DECO*27-san's 'Ai Kotoba' series, 4! 'Ai Kotoba IV'!
拍手いっぱい来てる！みんなありがとう！ギフトとかスパチャもありがとうございます！
So many claps are coming in! Thank you, everyone! Thank you for the gifts and Super Chats as well!
はい、今日ね、たくさん歌って踊らせていただくんですけど、感想とか、あとスクリーンショットとかは、ここ！
Yes, I'm going to sing and dance a lot today, but for your thoughts or screenshots, post them here!
「#風真いろは生誕LIVE2025」で、たくさんポストしてください！振り返りの時に見に行きますからねー！
Please make lots of posts using '#KazamaIrohaBirthdayLive2025'! I'll go check them during the review stream!
そして、今回なんと！誕生日用のステージを作っていただきましたー！
And this time, guess what! They created a special birthday stage for me!
かわいいー！ぽこべぇ、お前ディスプレイに載ったんかー！
So cute! Pokobe, did you get put on the display?!
いや、どこに行って言ってたかと思ったらディスプレイになっておりました。はい。そして後ろにも書いてあります。
I was wondering where you went, and it turns out you became part of the display. Yes. And it's also written behind me.
今回の風真いろはのライブタイトル、「Reversible」になってます！素敵なロゴ、柊先生ありがとうございました。
The title of this Kazama Iroha live show is "Reversible"! Thank you, Hiiragi-sensei, for the wonderful logo.
こちらですね、みんな昨日のカウントダウン配信では、ちょっと「ありゃ？」みたいな、どんなのだろうって、まだはてなはてなの方が多かったと思うんですが、
Regarding this, I think many of you were a bit like, "Huh? What could it be?" with lots of question marks during yesterday's countdown stream,
今回これ全編観てもらったらちゃんとわかるようになっておりますので、最後までお楽しみください！そして、事前にお伝えしていました通り、今回、風真いろは、
but if you watch the whole show today, you will completely understand, so please enjoy it until the very end! And, as previously announced, this time, Kazama Iroha...
100万人記念グッズが発売決定しましたー！
...will be releasing her 1 Million Subscribers Commemorative Goods!
いきなり来るよー！というわけで、今日は本当にまた告知溜めすぎてるので、ちょいちょい挟んでいきたいと思います。
It's coming out of nowhere! So, because I have piled up way too many announcements today, I'll be sharing them here and there.
はい、風真いろは100万人記念グッズはこちらです！それでは詳細見ていきましょう。
Yes, here are Kazama Iroha's 1 Million Subscribers Commemorative Goods! Let's take a look at the details.
はい、まずは、うみぼうずママが描いてくださった素敵なアクリルスタンド！
First, we have this wonderful acrylic stand illustrated by Umibozu-mama!
アクリルスタンドに、こう風真も一匹、そ、添えさせていただいておりますので、ぜひ皆さんこちら、ぜひお手に取っていただいて、メッセージゆっくり読んでください。ぽこべぇもいます。
We also have one Kazama placed alongside it, so please get your hands on this and take your time reading the message. Pokobe is there too.
そして次がこちら、パブ、パブ、パブミラー！すごいちょっと言いづらいんだよな、これリハの時から思ってたんですけど。
And next is this... pub, pub, pub mirror! It's actually a bit hard to pronounce, which I've been thinking ever since the rehearsal.
はい、パブミラーです！結構大きいです。風真が出したグッズの中でも、こう硬くて、なんかこの立てかける系の中で、タオルとかはあったけど、かなり大きめになってますので、
Yes, a pub mirror! It's quite large. Among the merchandise I've released, it's solid, and compared to other items you lean against things—we've had towels before, but this is quite large—
あの皆さんぜひ、こちらもメッセージ一筆書かせていただいておりますので、ぜひ飾ってもらえたら嬉しいです。そしてそして次！
so everyone, I've also written a message on this one, and I'd be very happy if you displayed it. And next!
はい、ランダムラバーストラップ！今回は100万人にちなみまして、風真いろは、今オリジナル曲複数出させていただいているんですけど、そちらのモチーフ衣装をラバーストラップにさせていただきました！
Yes, random rubber straps! This time, to celebrate 1 million subscribers, since I've released multiple original songs, we've turned their motif outfits into rubber straps!
かぜのともとかね、
So for the Kaze-no-tomo too,
実はなかなかグッズがなかったんですけど、今回
we actually didn't have much merch, but this time
の、ために、作らせていただきました！
I had them made just for you!
ぜひね、みんな色々集めて痛バとかの制作に
Please collect them all to help you make your anime bags
役立てていただければと思います！
and things like that!
次！
Next!
カードホルダー！
Card holder!
昨今、皆さんホロカとかね、色々なカードとか
Lately, you all have HoloKa and various cards
チェキ風のグッズが出ておりますので、
and instax-style merch coming out,
ついに作りました！ぽこべえのカードホルダーです！
so I finally made a Pokobe card holder!
定期入れにしてもよし、
It works as a pass case,
学生さんにも使っていただけたら嬉しいです。
and I'd be happy if students used it too.
みんなお気に入りの風真のカードとか飾ってくださいね！
Please use it to display your favorite Kazama card!
はい！それでは次！
Alright, next!
こちらフルセット、
Here is the full set,
このようになっておりまして、
it looks like this...
そして今回、購入特典は、はい！
And the bonus for buying the full set is...
うみぼうずママ描き下ろしのステッカーにさせていただきました！
this sticker specially illustrated by Umibozu-mama!
今回はですね、
This time around,
こちら直筆サインの数量限定版はありませんので、
there is no limited edition with handwritten autographs,
あの、皆さん安心してゆっくり買ってくださいね！
so you can all buy it at your own pace without worry!
はい！
Yes!
というわけで、100万人記念グッズ紹介でございました！
And that was the introduction of the 1 million milestone goods!
うわー、ドキドキ。
Wow, my heart is racing.
なんか結構、安心しきってるんですけど、
I actually feel quite relieved now, but...
あの、もうこれだけじゃなくてですね、後半も、
this isn't the only thing. In the second half,
あの、告知がありすぎて、頑張って入れるしかなかったぐらいには
there are so many announcements we had to squeeze them in,
いっぱいあるんで、告知いっぱいあります。
so we have tons of announcements!
なので、あの、皆さん絶対に見逃さないでください。
So please, make sure you don't miss them.
え、もうトレンド1位なんですか！？
Wait, we are already trending at #1!?
始まったばっかりだよ！
But we've only just started!
いいの！？
Is this really okay!?
みんなありがとう！！
Thank you, everyone!!
うそ！みんなありがとうございます！
No way! Thank you all so much!
いや、すごい。
Wow, this is amazing.
めちゃ、こんなに早く行くと思わなくって、
I didn't think we'd hit it so quickly,
皆さんのおかげです。本当にありがとうございます！
it's all thanks to you. Thank you so much!
で、ちょっとお水飲んで、
Now I'll drink some water,
次の曲バシバシ行きたいと思います！
and head straight into the next song!
お待たせしました！
Thank you for waiting!
お水をいっぱい飲んだので、
Since I've had plenty of water,
この力をそのまま、すべてフルパワーで出力いたします！
I will release all of this energy at full power!
それでは皆殿、次の曲、聴いてください！
Now everyone, please listen to the next song!
「大きな愛でもてなして」
"Welcome Me with a Big Love"!
大きな愛でもてなして
Welcome me with a big love
そこんとこ大事なことよ
That point is very important
大きな愛でもてなして
Welcome me with a big love
わがままでいいのよ
It's okay to be selfish, you know
私は勝つの
I will win
寂しがり屋だと
Because I get lonely easily
泣きそうよ
I feel like crying
Oh Yeah Oh Yeah
一日の
Even within
間でも
a single day
告白をしたり
either confessing love
キスしたり
or kissing
一日が大変
The day is so hectic
大人より
More than adults
相当 濃いゆいのです
it is extremely dense
相当 長いのです
it is extremely long
等身大
True-to-life size
大きな愛でもてなして
Welcome me with a big love
そこんとこ気持ちは大事よ
For that, feelings are important
大きな愛でもてなして
Welcome me with a big love
そういうルールになってる
Those are the rules
みんな知らないふり
Everyone pretends not to know
他人の事だと
Thinking it's someone else's business
違うのよ
But they're wrong
Oh Yeah Oh Yeah
明日はまた新しい
Tomorrow there will be a new
恋愛があれば
romance, and if there is,
逆戻り
I'll go backwards
Oh Yeah Oh Yeah
大人より
More than adults
そう特に
yes, especially,
たくさん恋できちゃう
I can fall in love many times
等身大
True-to-life size
明日はまた新しい
Tomorrow there will be a new
恋愛があれば 逆戻り
romance, and if there is, I'll go backwards
大人より正直
More honest than adults,
そっと君に
gently to you...
たくさん恋できちゃう
I can fall in love so many times!
たくさん恋できちゃう そうみたい
I can fall in love so many times, it seems so!
大きな愛でもてなして
Treat me with a big love!
ありえない幻想 あふれだす妄想
An impossible fantasy, an overflowing delusion,
君以外全部いらないわ
I don't need anything other than you!
息をするように嘘ついても
Even if I lie as naturally as breathing,
あたしやっぱりいらない子？
am I still an unwanted child after all?
こぼれ出しちゃった承認欲求
My overflowing desire for recognition...
もっとココロ満たしてよ
Please satisfy my heart more!
アスパルテーム 甘い夢
Aspartame, a sweet dream...
あたしだけに愛をください
Please give love only to me.
あーもう無理 混ざり混ざり 恋して愛して救済執行バッドね
Ah, it's too much, mixing and mingling, fall in love, love me, salvation execution is bad, right?
ねえ 好きって言ってよ？
Hey, tell me you love me!
ありえない幻想 あふれだす妄想
An impossible fantasy, an overflowing delusion...
つまんないつまんない欲求が散らばって
Boring, boring desires are scattered!
求めてる愛情 隠してる劣情
The affection I seek, the base passions I hide...
君以外全部いらないわ
I don't need anything other than you!
Yeah
誰のこと見ているの？
Who are you looking at?
こういうの好きなの？
Do you like this kind of thing?
DDとかガチでやめてください
Seriously, stop loving everyone, please!
かわいくなりたい
I want to be cute!
キラキラしてたい
I want to sparkle!
もっともっとガチで褒めてください
Please praise me much, much more, seriously!
泣いちゃう散々
I'll cry terribly!
あけちゃうシャンパン
Let's pop some champagne!
今夜も配信来てくれるよね？
You'll come to my stream tonight too, right?
独占させてよ
Let me monopolize you!
本命なんでしょ
I'm your favorite, right?
もっともっとガチで推してください
Please support me much, much more, seriously!
飲みすぎ注意 オーバードーズ
Careful not to drink too much, overdose...
クラクラさせて いつだって
Make me dizzy, always!
あーもう無理 混ざり混ざり 上がって下がって救済執行バッドね
Ah, it's too much, mixing and mingling, rising and falling, salvation execution is bad, right?
ねえ 好きって言わせて？
Hey, let me say I love you!
噛みついた衝動 戻れない衝動
The biting impulse, the irreversible impulse...
たまんないミッドナイト 指が絡まって
Unbearable midnight, fingers intertwined...
ときめいた表情 何も言わないで
A fluttered expression, don't say anything...
君だけがきっと 王子様
Only you are surely my prince!
ありえない幻想 あふれだす妄想
An impossible fantasy, an overflowing delusion...
つまんないつまんない欲求が散らばって
Boring, boring desires are scattered!
求めてる愛情 隠してる劣情
The affection I seek, the base passions I hide...
君以外全部いらないわ
I don't need anything other than you!
あたしだけずっと 追いかけて！
Chase only after me forever!
ねえ、もう待てないの
Hey, I can't wait any longer...
君以外全部いらないわ
I don't need anything other than you!
絶対 アイドル辞めないで
Never stop being an idol!
ずっと
Forever...
輝いてる君を見たい
I want to see you shining!
もう ずっとずっとずっと
For much, much longer,
ステージにいて
stay on the stage!
私がもし君のとこ 離れたなら
If I were to leave your side...
君はちょっと寂しくなるかな
Would you feel a bit lonely?
いじわる考える
I play with these mean thoughts.
好きな人がいるのなら 内緒にして
If there is someone you love, keep it a secret.
ねえ
Hey,
神様は将来と指輪を
God, please hide our future and wedding ring
どこかに隠してて
somewhere.
君の「好き」に合わせたんだ 髪の色
I matched my hair color to what you like.
私の中 君だけで
Inside of me, there is only you.
過剰摂取は中毒へ
An overdose leads to addiction.
責任とってね 大好きです
Take responsibility, okay? I love you so much!
せーの！
One, two!
絶対 アイドル辞めないで
Never stop being an idol!
ずっと
Forever...
優しい目も 真面目顔も
Your gentle eyes, your serious face...
全て知ってる私が言う！
I, who knows all of them, am saying this!
絶対 空で輝いて
You must shine in the sky!
ずっと
Forever...
星は街じゃ輝かないの
Stars don't shine in the city streets,
眩しい君が世界一だよ
you, who are so dazzling, are the best in the world!
Wow...
君の夢は何ですか？
What is your dream?
教えてほしい
I want you to tell me.
その夢がアイドルじゃなくても 覚悟はしてるから
Even if that dream is not to be an idol, I'm prepared for it.
星のない空 それが当たり前で
A sky without stars, that was only natural,
暗い道に目が慣れずに 踏み出すのも怖かった
My eyes couldn't adapt to the dark path, and I was too scared to step forward.
そんな時やっと見えた光
But that's when I finally saw the light.
絶対君は歌っていて
You must keep singing forever.
誰の我が儘か分かっていても 君はキラキラ衣装が似合う
Even if I know it's just someone's selfishness, sparkly outfits suit you perfectly.
絶対大きなステージで
You must stand on a massive stage forever.
1等星よりも前で輝く 君の歌い方なんか好きだな
Shining brighter than the first-magnitude star, I think I really love the way you sing.
君の努力と私の愛 成り立つこの関係は
Your hard work and my love, this relationship we build
強くて脆いな 星の幸せを願った
Is both strong and fragile. I prayed for my star's happiness.
だけど
And yet...
でもね だって君はアイドルよ ずっと
But you see, after all, you are an idol, forever.
初めて出会った日から 今日も明日も君ばかりだ
Since the day we first met, today and tomorrow, my mind is filled with you.
絶対アイドル辞めないで
Please, never stop being an idol.
これは報われないお伽話 恋より重い「もっと」好きだ
This is an unrewarded fairy tale, a love heavier than love, I love you "more."
魔法よどうか解けないままで
Oh magic, please never fade away.
Wow...
UNHAPPY?
悩める人の子よ
O troubled child of man,
UNLUCKY?
人成らざる者も
And those who are not human,
絶えず目指せよ
Never cease to strive,
生きているんだし
After all, you are alive!
目を逸らした過去も
The past you averted your eyes from,
退屈な未来も
And the boring future,
カウンセリング やれやれ
We'll counsel them all, good grief.
古今東西 ピースピース
Far and wide, peace, peace!
UNHAPPY?
UNLUCKY?
BE HAPPY?
UNDEAD!
ねえねえねえ なんだかどうして 戦っているようなそんな気がするの
Hey, hey, hey, why does it feel like I'm constantly fighting?
過去の自分と
With my past self,
もうとっくに死んでる 幽霊と対決
Confronting a ghost of me that has long since died.
痛い手で痛い 記憶の落とし前
Settling the score of painful memories with aching hands.
もう居ないのに
Even though they are no longer here.
あれ？そっちが良い？アイロニーね
Oh? Is that better? How ironic.
透かされているのは 現在の自分
The one being seen through is my current self.
ナンセンス 消えないレッテル
Nonsense, an indelible label,
要はコンプレックスに取り憑かれているみたい
Essentially, I seem to be possessed by complexes,
掻き毟ったまま
Scratching away at them.
まだ離れない ありし日の自分
The self from those bygone days still won't leave.
死んじゃいない
I'm not dead!
お前とお前の連鎖
The chain of you and your past.
生きていることは変わり続けることだ
To live is to continue changing.
不幸に甘んじて満足するなよ
Don't content yourself with wallowing in unhappiness!
幸せになろうとしないなんて卑怯だ
Refusing to strive for happiness is just cowardly!
この世この世は 奇怪奇怪ファンタジー
This world, this world is a bizarre fantasy.
次は鬼が出るか蛇が出るか
Will a demon or a serpent appear next?
出会って違ってやっと始まる物語
Meeting, differing, the story finally begins.
さあ人か化け物か 覚悟は良い？ピースピース
Now, human or monster, are you ready? Peace, peace!
Past & Future can't change the Past
Past & Future run for the Future
なんだかどうして 未来になんぞ何の
For some reason, I feel like...
ような気がしても
...the future holds nothing for me.
もう大分生きている 既視感とテンプレで食傷
I've lived quite a while, sick of déjà vu and templates.
素敵な出来事も気配もない
There's no sign of any wonderful events either.
残念 積んだ経験の因果
Regrettably, the causality of accumulated experience
形骸化された神話と退屈な進化
Has led to formalized myths and boring evolution.
要は刺激が欲しいんだ 飽きちゃった
In short, I want some excitement. I'm bored.
ナンセンス 整っていくガイダンス 増えるコンプライアンス
Nonsense, orderly guidance and growing compliance,
塞がれていくみたい 吸い尽くして
It feels like being suffocated, squeezed dry.
あれも これも どれも 同じ味がする
This, that, and everything else all taste the same.
死んじゃいない
I'm not dead!
お前とお前の連鎖
The chain of you and your past.
何時の世も過去も未来も 現在にあるんだ
In any era, the past and the future both exist in the present!
生きていることを 愚直に果たせよ
Fulfill the act of living with honest devotion!
目指せハピネス
Aim for happiness!
UNDEAD!
死んじゃいない お前に言っているんだ
You're not dead! I'm talking to you.
幸せを諦めてしまうな 人であれ
Don't give up on happiness. Remain human!
ただ苦しみに慣れて 耐えているだけじゃ
Just getting used to suffering and enduring it
死んでいるも同然 屍のアンデッド
Is as good as being dead—a corpse of an undead.
UNHAPPY?
悩める人の子よ
O troubled child of man,
UNLUCKY?
人成らざる者も
And those who are not human,
絶えず目指せよ
Never cease to strive,
生きているんだろ
After all, you are alive!
不幸に浸るな
Don't indulge in unhappiness,
幸せになろう
Let's become happy!
そう全部全部お前のもの
Yes, it is all, entirely yours!
my inside が最新の森羅万象 ピース ピース
My inside is the latest creation, peace peace.
Past & Future can't change the Past
Past & Future run for the Future
人の在る所に 何時も憂い事
Wherever people are, there is always sorrow.
生き抜けこの化物ばかりの物騙り
Survive through this tale full of monsters.
Reversible
[Title: Reversible]
真夜中に告ぐ 音の警鐘
A warning sound chiming at midnight,
今日はおによう 午前零時
greeting you with 'Oniyou' at 12:00 AM.
あなたが触れる 光 揺らぎ 熱
You touch the light, the sway, the heat...
指先に 踊らされ
controlled by your fingertips.
感覚 即 体感
Sense quickly turns to experience,
静まる夜 二人だけの密
in the quiet night, our own secret.
感覚 即 快感
Sense quickly turns to pleasure,
重なる波形に 魅了されていく
being captivated by the overlapping waveforms.
忘れないでね 私の声を
Please don't forget my voice,
画面越しでいい ちゃんと愛して
even through a screen, love me properly.
バーチャルだって 突き放さないで
Even if I'm virtual, don't push me away,
あなたの音に まだ溺れていたい
I still want to drown in your sound.
覚えていてね 私の声を
Please remember my voice,
あなたがくれた この身すべてを
everything of this body that you gave me.
見つめ合う あなたと二人
Gazing at each other, just the two of us,
重ねた 息と音とヒビカセ
our overlapping breaths and sounds, let them resonate!
真夜中に問う 冷え切った熱
Questioning in the midnight, a chilled heat,
待ち続けてる 午前零時
waiting continuously at 12:00 AM.
鏡写しに 飽和していく
Saturating in the mirror's reflection,
知らない 音が伝う
an unfamiliar sound travels through.
感覚 即 体感
Sense quickly turns to experience,
静まる夜と 息遣い揃う
In the quiet night, our breathing falls into sync.
感覚 即 快感
Sense quickly turns to pleasure,
錆びたロジック「今一度」を焦がれる
Rusted logic, yearning for 'once more'.
忘れないでね 私の声を
Please don't forget my voice,
次元も超えて 飛ばすシグナル
crossing dimensions, I send out a signal.
バーチャルだなんて 言わないで
Don't say things like 'it's virtual'...
あなたの音に まだ愛されていたい
I still want to be loved by your sound.
覚えていてね 私の声を
Please remember my voice,
あなたがくれた この身すべてを
everything of this body that you gave me.
言葉のハット 初音とマッチ
A hat of words, matching with the first sound,
交わるこの息と音とヒビカセ
intersecting, this breath and sound, let them resonate!
あぁ あなたの生んだ音に
Ah, to the sound you created,
あたしが命を宿したら
if I were to breathe life into it,
哀しみ 怒り 歓喜 全部
sadness, anger, joy, everything,
打ち鳴らす
I will let it ring out!
絶えず叫ぶ 声連ねる
Constantly shouting, lining up my voices,
余熱焦せる 愛、絶艶く
with lingering heat, a scorching love blooming beautifully.
絶えず叫ぶ 声連ねる
Constantly shouting, lining up my voices,
余熱焦せる 愛、絶艶く
with lingering heat, a scorching love blooming beautifully.
魅了されていく
...captivated.
忘れないでね 私の声を
Please don't forget my voice,
画面越しでいい ちゃんと愛して
even through a screen, love me properly.
バーチャルだって 突き放さないで
Even if I'm virtual, don't push me away,
あなたの音に まだ溺れていたい
I still want to drown in your sound.
覚えていてね 私の声を
Please remember my voice,
あなたがくれた この身すべてを
everything of this body that you gave me.
というわけで
And so...
皆さん、新衣装になりました！
Everyone, I got a new outfit!
どうですか？
How is it?
か、かっこいいですか？
Is it... Is it cool?
なんと、今回はダンスを頑張ると決めた、そん時から決めていた
This time, I decided to do my best in dancing, I had decided it from then...
ちょっとかっこいい系のダンス衣装になってみました！
I tried on a slightly cool-style dance outfit!
イエイ！
Yay!
皆さん写真いっぱい撮って、撮って、撮って、撮って！
Everyone, take lots of photos, take them, take them, take them!
イエイ、かっこいいでしょ！
Yay, it's cool, right?
えっと、可愛いばっかなんだけど
Wait, there are only "cute" comments...
かっこいいはどこ行ったんだよ？
Where did "cool" go?
かっこいいはどこ行ったんだよ！
Where did "cool" go?!
はい、というわけで新衣装になりました。
Yes, and so, I got a new outfit.
ゲストパートの「絶対アイドル辞めないで」から、ソロになりまして「Undead」「ヒビカセ」と続けてお送りさせていただきました！
Following the guest part with "Zettai Idol Yamenaide," I went solo and performed "Undead" and "Hibikase" back-to-back!
どうでしたか？
How was it?
めっちゃ頑張って…足ちぎれそうってそういうことです、本当にたくさん今回は
I worked super hard... "my legs are about to fall off" is literally what I mean. Really, this time...
変身のために飛びました！
I jumped high to transform!
足がちぎれそうです。
My legs are about to fall off.
「絶対アイドル辞めないで」でもね、先輩方、そしてラプラスも来てくれて
For "Zettai Idol Yamenaide," the senpais and also La+ came!
ありがとう！激ムズだったね、本当に！
Thank you! It was super difficult, seriously!
本当に激ムズでしたね！
It really was super difficult!
皆さん、一緒に頑張ってくださり本当にありがとうございました！
Everyone, thank you so much for working hard with me!
そ、そしてですね、あの
A-And then, um...
この後もまだまだゲストさんたくさん呼んでおります！そして、ござるも
We still have many guests coming up after this! And I...
実は、このカラーリングだけじゃ実は無いんですよ！なので
Actually, this coloring isn't the only one! So...
そちらも公開していくので、皆様お楽しみに！
I will be revealing that as well, so please look forward to it!
それでは、次はゲストさんと一緒に歌わせていただきます！
Well then, next, I will sing together with a guest!
それでは、どうぞ！
Without further ado, here it is!
ブラックロックシューター　何処へ行ったの？
Black Rock Shooter, where did you go?
聴こえますか？
Can you hear me?
あとどれだけ叫べばいいんだろう
How much more do I have to scream?
あとどれだけ泣けばいいんだろう
How much more do I have to cry?
もうやめて　わたしはもう走れない
Stop it already, I can't run anymore.
いつか夢見た世界が閉じる
The world I once dreamed of is closing.
真っ暗で明かりもない
It's pitch black with no light...
崩れかけたこの道で
...on this crumbling road.
あるはずもないあの時の希望が
The hope of that time that shouldn't even exist...
見えた気がした　どうして
...I felt like I saw it. Why?
ブラックロックシューター　懐かしい記憶
Black Rock Shooter, fond memories...
ただ楽しかったあの頃を
...of those days that were just fun.
ブラックロックシューター　でも動けないよ
Black Rock Shooter, but I cannot move.
闇を駆ける星に願いを
Wish upon a star running through the darkness...
もう一度だけ走るから
...because I will run just one more time!
怖くて震える声で呟く
Muttering with a scared, trembling voice,
わたしの名前を呼んで
"Call my name."
夜明けを抱く空　境界線までの距離
The sky embracing dawn, the distance to the boundary line...
あと一歩届かない
...is just one step out of reach.
こらえた涙が溢れそうなの
My held-back tears are about to overflow.
今下を向かないで　止まってしまう
Don't look down now, or you'll stop completely.
未来を生きていたいんだ　わかったの
I want to live in the future, I understand now!
思い出して強く、強く信じるの
Remember it, and believe strongly, strongly!
そうよ
Yes, indeed!
ブラックロックシューター　優しい匂い
Black Rock Shooter, a gentle scent...
痛いよ　辛いよ　飲み込む言葉
It hurts, it's hard, swallowing my words...
ブラックロックシューター　動いてこの足！
Black Rock Shooter, move, my legs!
はもう走れない
...I can't run anymore.
世界が閉じる
The world is closing...
最初から分かっていた
I knew it from the start...
ここにいることを
...that I'd be here.
あたしのなかの
All of the...
すべての勇気が
...courage within me...
火をともして
...lights a fire.
もう逃げないよ
I won't run away anymore!
ブラック★ロックシューター
Black Rock Shooter!
ひとりじゃないよ
You are not alone!
声をあげて泣いたって構わない
It's okay to cry out loud!
ブラック★ロックシューター
Black Rock Shooter,
見ていてくれる
watching over me.
今から始まるの
It starts right now,
あたしの物語
my own story!
忘れそうになったら この歌を
If you're about to forget, this song...
歌うの
...I will sing.
Beyond the way
言い切った言葉ばかりで
Only with words said with certainty,
古い退屈な夜満ちて
the old, boring night is filled.
ルールは無視でいきたいね
I want to go on ignoring the rules.
Shut up, shut up, ha
Saddle up, it's soul
化学反応じゃねえ
It's not a chemical reaction.
もうずっと言うこと聞いていられないくらい
To the point where I can't keep listening to you,
どうしようもない
...completely helpless.
Yeah, read between the lines
It's no fiction
You make me sigh, 何なんだ
You make me sigh, what is this?
I know the way
願ってるだけじゃ叶わない
Just wishing won't make it come true.
めちゃくちゃにしたって変わらない
Even if you mess things up, it won't change.
なら、クライ
So, climb...
超えて find a way
...transcend and find a way.
街のライト浴びる感覚はもういらない
I no longer need the feeling of bathing in city lights.
ピント違いですから、聞き飽きたわ
Because it's totally off-focus, I'm tired of hearing it.
連れていけるところまで take me higher
To the point where I can take you, take me higher.
ちょっと情緒不安定、無理、撤退
A bit emotionally unstable, impossible, retreat!
本気は分かってるでしょ
You know I'm serious, right?
Saddle up, it's soul
化学反応じゃねえ
It's not a chemical reaction.
もうずっとちゃんと言わない、あれは誰のせい？
You won't say it properly, whose fault is that?
終わらない夢を描こう 願ったまま
Let's draw an endless dream just as we wished,
欲しがったまま
just as we wanted.
終わらない夜を越えていこう このまま
Let's cross over the endless night just like this,
心揺さぶるこの声
this voice that shakes the heart.
省きって消せない足跡
Footprints that cannot be omitted or erased,
粗相だとしても言っちゃえとか
even if it's a blunder, say "just say it,"
運命感じる感受性は
the sensitivity to feel destiny...
歪めない、うちら負けない
...won't be distorted, we won't lose!
超えて笑って 追っていつでも Number one
Surpass, laugh, chase, always number one.
そっとして そっとさせて 攻めて
Be quiet, let me be quiet, attack!
神のみぞ知るような
As if only God knows.
Yeah, yeah, 刺激まだまだ
Yeah, yeah, the excitement is far from over!
Go beyond the way, yeah
言い切った言葉ばかりで
Only with words said with certainty,
古い言葉を探して
searching for old words.
歩み研ぎ澄まし 誇り 従がって行け
Sharpening your steps, and with pride, follow.
Are we on the way now? Find my, find my heart
Uh-uh-uh-uh...
終わらない夢を描こう 願ったまま
Let's draw an endless dream just as we wished,
欲しがったまま
just as we wanted.
はい！というわけで本日は
Yes! So today...
このお二人に来ていただきました！
...I've invited these two to join me!
わー！来たよ！ / お邪魔します！
Yay! We're here! / Excuse us!
ありがとう！ / お祝い！ / おめでとう！
Thank you! / Congratulations! / Happy birthday!
お誕生日おめでとうございました！
Happy birthday to you!
ありがとうございます！
Thank you so much!
お忙しいのに お二人とも 今日はね
Thank you both for coming even though you're busy.
ずっとレッスンからお付き合いいただき ありがとうございました！
Thank you so much for sticking with me since the lessons!
こちらこそありがとうございました！
Thank you so much as well!
今回はですね 誕生日で 実は衣装が...
For my birthday this time, actually my outfit...
白くて可愛い！ / おへそ見えてる！
It's white and cute! / Your belly button is showing!
そう、そう。やばい、取られる。
Yes, yes. Oh no, they're showing it off!
白可愛い！ / ツインテール似合ってる！
The white is so cute! / The twin-tails suit you!
そうなんです。新しくね、ダンスする用みたいなね、衣装になったので、これは...
That's right. Since I got a new outfit for dancing...
恐れ多くも、二人を呼ぼうかなと。
...I thought of calling the two of you, even though I was nervous.
ダンスが上手いお二人を 呼んでもいいかな？って 呼ばせていただきました。
I asked if I could invite two great dancers, and here you are.
ええ！？ / あなた方、あなた方です。
What!? / Yes, you two, of course!
最初、楽しかった！ / 楽しかった！
It was so much fun! / It was fun!
レッスンもね、一緒に頑張っていただきまして。
Thank you for working hard together during lessons.
お二人ともめちゃくちゃ元が良いから、風真一人だけどうしようかな、これ。
Since both of you are naturally so good, Kazama didn't know what to do on her own.
そんなことないよ！めっちゃ踊ってた！<
That's not true! You danced so much!
めっちゃ踊った。最高のものが出来たと思います。
I danced a lot. I think we made something awesome.
みんな、良いのできたよね？って、今頃コメントにも流れてると思います！
Everyone, we did a great job, right? I bet the comments are saying that!
だって、いろはちゃんと初めてじゃん？
After all, it's our first time, right?
一緒にダンスすること。こういうフォーメーションダンス初めてさ。
Dancing together. It's our first time doing a formation dance like this.
ね、めっちゃ嬉しい！ / 本当に誘ってよかった！
Yeah, I'm so happy! / I'm so glad I invited you!
お二人とも、この期間一緒に踊って、めちゃくちゃ勉強になりました。先生方！
Dancing with both of you during this period, I learned so much. Teachers!
そんなことないですよ！ありがとうございました！
That's not true at all! Thank you very much!
またね、何かあったらぜひ一緒に踊って...
If anything comes up again, let's definitely dance...
ぜひ！一緒にやりましょう！やりましょう！
Definitely! Let's do it! Let's do it together!
じゃあ、ちょっとこの記念に、友情の証、強い、かっこいいポーズ、写真撮っとこう。かっこいいポーズ。
Then, to commemorate this, as a sign of friendship, let's take a picture in a tough, cool pose. A cool pose.
かっこいいポーズ？ / かっこいいポーズ！
A cool pose? / A cool pose!
かっこいいポーズが思いつかない！何だ？
I can't think of a cool pose! What is this?
かわいいよ。 / かわいい、めっちゃかわいい！
It's cute. / Cute, super cute!
まぁいっか。みんなたくさんSNSに投稿してくださいね。
Oh well. Everyone, please post lots of them on SNS.
はい。と言いつつ、実はですね、もう一つお願いがあって。
Yes. Having said that, actually, I have one more request.
今日この後、今日初お披露目のオリ曲があるんです！
After this, today I'm debuting a new original song!
オリ曲！？すごい！楽しみだ！どんな曲？
Original song!? Awesome! Can't wait! What kind of song?
やっぱり風真いろは、かっこよくなりたくて。今回は、かっこいい曲を持ってまいりました！
After all, Kazama Iroha wants to be cool. So this time, I brought a cool song!
おー！かっこいい！楽しみ！
Oh! Cool! Can't wait!
かわいくてかっこいいお二人から、やっぱちょっと勇気をもらってから行こうかなと。
So, I thought I'd get some courage from the two of you, who are cute and cool, before I go.
かっこいいビーム！ / せーの、ふー、わぁー！
Cool beam! / Ready, set, whoosh!
すごい！なんか、ちょっとイケメンになってきた気がする！ちょっとイケメンのポーズ分かんない、こう？
Amazing! I feel like I've become a bit cool! Wait, I don't know a cool pose, like this?
いいよ、かっこいいよ！いけてる、いけてる！
Nice, that's cool! Looking good, looking cool!
よし！お二人からめちゃくちゃエネルギーもらえたんで、頑張ってきます！
Alright! Since I got so much energy from both of you, I'll do my best!
お二人とも今日は本当にお祝いと、そして一緒に歌って踊ってくれて、ありがとうございました！
Thank you both so much for today's celebration, and for singing and dancing with me!
こちらこそありがとうございました！ / また遊びましょうね！
Thank you as well! / Let's play again!
はい、じゃあそれでは、この後、新オリ曲を初お披露目させていただきます！せーの...
All right, then next, I will debut my new original song! Ready, set...
どうぞー！
Go ahead!
見た目だけじゃわからない
You can't tell just by looking...
ワタシのこと 可愛いだけと
...that I'm not just cute.
まさか思っていないよね？
Surely you don't think that, right?
ワタシのホント...
My true...
知っていてほしい
...I want you to know.
Passion Passion
Burning
Emotion
予測誤差の範囲と 不測の事態も動じない
Unshaken by the margin of prediction error and unexpected events,
おすましフェイスでいるけど 心は常に青白く燃える
I keep a straight face, but my heart is always burning with a pale flame.
諦めはしない 媚びたりもしない ワタシを曲げない
I won't give up, I won't flatter, I won't compromise myself.
可愛い見かけで 扱いやすい奴だと思うな あまく見ると 痛い目みるぞ
Don't think I'm easy to handle just because of my cute looks. Underestimate me, and you'll regret it.
それでも ときには 逃げ出してしまいたい
Even so, there are times when I just want to run away.
そんな衝動に 弱音吐きたくなる真夜中もある
Caught by such impulses, there are midnights when I want to whine.
ほんの小さな小さな妥協が 積み重なり重なって動けない
Merely small, tiny compromises pile up, and I find myself unable to move.
大きな大きな可能性失くし 未来を狭めてしまうから
Losing great, massive potential will only narrow my future.
Passion Passion Glowing
どんなに暗くても 辛くても 後悔だけはしない
No matter how dark or painful, I will never have regrets.
イケてるのは見た目じゃなくて 生きかたなんだ
What makes me cool isn't my looks, but the way I live.
現実と理想との 距離を縮められたとしても
Even if the gap between reality and my ideals could be bridged,
おすましフェイスでいるだけ 何事もなかったかのように
I would just keep a straight face as if nothing happened.
立ち止まりはしない 後戻りもしない 夢を捨てない
I won't stop, I won't turn back, I won't throw away my dreams.
可愛い見かけで 頼りないとか 弱そうとか 決めつけないで 全部が私
Don't assume I'm unreliable or weak just by my cute looks. This is all of me.
それでも ときには 温もりが恋しい
Even so, there are times when I long for warmth.
そんな感情に 流されてしまいそうな真夜中もある
There are midnights when I feel like getting swept away by such feelings.
こんな甘い甘いことだけ 求められてしまうような 弱さ要らない
I don't need the weakness that makes me crave only sweet things.
苦い苦い経験だって ワタシを強くしてくれるから
Because even bitter, harsh experiences make me stronger.
Passion Passion Emotion
これが これが ワタシの ホント
This, this is the real me.
とても狭い狭い世界の中だけで 終わらせたくはないんだ
I don't want to let it end inside this tiny, narrow world.
広い広い世界の果てまで 駆け抜けて生きていくんだから
Because I'm going to run through to the end of this vast, wide world.
Passion Passion Glowing
どんなに険しくて過酷でも 楽しんでやるさ
No matter how steep or harsh, I'm going to enjoy it.
イケてるのは見た目じゃなくて 生きかたなんだから
Because what makes me cool isn't my looks, but the way I live!
はい。というわけで、皆さん、ゲストパートから続けて新オリジナル曲「ホントノワタシ」歌って踊らせていただきました！
Yes! And so, everyone, continuing from the guest segment, I got to sing and dance to my new original song, "Honto no Watashi"!
なんと風真いろは、7曲目のオリジナル曲です！
It's actually Kazama Iroha's seventh original song!
新オリジナル曲のジャケットも届いているので見ていきましょう。こちらです！
The cover art for the new original song is here, so let's check it out. Here it is!
はい。こちらの風真いろは新オリジナル曲、7曲目「ホントノワタシ」は、こちら、日付変わりまして、19日0時よりリリースされることとなりました！
Yes, this seventh original song by Kazama Iroha, "Honto no Watashi," is set to be released at midnight on the 19th!
今回の新衣装に因んで、こちら作っていただきました！
This was created in connection with my new outfit for this live stream!
はい。ちょっと今までとだいぶ系統の違う曲になるんですけれども。あの、いつもみんなね、ありがたいことに風真いろはのこと「かっこいい」っていうよりは「かわいい」って言ってくださる方がいっぱいいるので、
Yes, it's a song with a very different vibe from my previous ones. Many people are kind enough to tell me that I'm cute rather than cool,
「いや、かっこいいとこもあるんだよ！」っていうのを伝えたくて作らせていただきました！
so I wanted to show that I have a cool side too! That's why I had this song made.
こちら、ぜひ0時にリリースされたらたくさん聴いて、またハッシュタグとか、見て、見てるいろはなので、感想とか教えていただいたら嬉しいです！
Once it's released at midnight, please listen to it a lot, and since I'll be checking the hashtag, I'd love it if you could share your thoughts!
そしてそして、ゲストパートについてもお話ししていきますかね。ちょっと戻って、
And now, let's talk about the guest segment as well. Let's go back...
はい、ゲストでね、みお先輩と、そして、はじめちゃん、べー先輩と一緒に歌って躍らせていただきました！
Yes, for the guest part, I got to sing and dance with Mio-senpai, Hajime-chan, and Bae-senpai!
みお先輩、そしてべー、そしてはじめちゃん、来てくれてありがとう！
Mio-senpai, Bae, and Hajime-chan, thank you so much for coming!
もう本当に歌も難しかったし、べー...
The song was really difficult, and Bae...
…ねえと、初めてのやつに関してはマジこれができなさすぎて、
Regarding the first one, I was seriously so bad at it...
一生やりすぎて、
I kept doing it over and over,
あの、一生腰痛を抱えて、これが結構筋肉痛の原因でした。
and I got bad lower back pain... This was the cause of my muscle soreness.
はい。
Yes.
でもすごい、一緒に歌って踊らせていただきまして、とってもとってもいい経験になりました。
But I got to sing and dance together, and it was a very, very good experience.
皆さん、ありがとうございました！
Everyone, thank you very much!
はい。ということで、次の曲に行く前に、
Yes. So, before moving on to the next song...
お水飲んでいいですか？お水飲みます。
Can I drink some water? I'm going to drink some water.
お水。
Water.
ロゴも見て！実は変わってた。
Look at the logo too! It actually changed.
よし。
Alright.
お待たせしました。
Thank you for waiting.
息整えて…はい。
Let me catch my breath... Yes.
次の曲なんですけれども、やっぱり
So, for the next song, as expected,
みんな「バラードも好きだよ」って言ってくれる方が多いので、
many of you said you also like ballads,
今回の生誕ライブ、バラードやろうと思って持ってきました。
so I decided to perform a ballad for this birthday live.
はい。ちょっとかっこいい感じに歌えるか、色々練習したんですけど、
Yes. I practiced a lot to see if I could sing it in a cool way,
ぜひ心を込めて歌うので、聴いていただけると嬉しいです。
and I will sing it with all my heart, so I hope you enjoy it.
それでは次の曲、お聞きください。
Now, please listen to the next song.
「W/X/Y」
"W/X/Y"
W/X/Y
作詞・作曲：Tani Yuuki
[W/X/Y
Lyrics & Composition: Tani Yuuki]
垂れ流したテレビの音
The sound of the TV left turned on,
溜めてしまった洗濯物は今日こそ
the laundry I've let pile up, today for sure.
晴れでもあえて外には出ないでいよう
Even if it's sunny, let's purposely not go outside,
映えないスナックとアルコールで乾杯をしよう
and let's make a toast with unphotogenic snacks and alcohol.
2人酸いも甘いも 噛み合わないとしても
Even if our sweet and sour moments don't match up,
お互い寄り添うように 少しずらしてみようよ
let's try shifting a little so we can lean on each other.
君がくれた太陽 月で隠れないように
So that the sun you gave me won't be hidden by the moon,
輝き絶えぬように 歌うメロディ 戯れる
so that it never stops shining, the melody I sing plays around.
Slowly flowingで
Slowly flowing,
愛してるも通り越して
moving beyond even "I love you",
似た者同士こうして
like-minded people, like this,
年老いるまでは笑っていたいね
I want us to keep laughing until we grow old.
君がいなきゃlonely lonely day
Without you, it's a lonely, lonely day.
夢の中 Fall asleep in bed
Falling asleep in bed inside a dream,
起こすから morning callで
I'll wake you up with a morning call.
I'll protect you from nightmares, Baby
脱ぎっぱなしの足跡辿ると
Following the footprints left by discarded clothes,
不意を突いて後ろから抱きつくの
catching me off guard, hugging me from behind.
つい、繰り返すと忘れてしまいそうになるよ//
If I casually repeat it, I feel like I might forget.
振り返ると日々が当たり前じゃないこと
When I look back, I realize these days are not to be taken for granted.
2人対の細胞 絡み合う特別な
Our paired cells, entangling in a special way,
噛み締めて生きたいと思った まどろみ抱く正午
I wanted to cherish them as I live, embracing the slumber at noon.
吐息漏れた体温 微熱逃がさないように//
Our temperature where sighs escaped, so as not to let the slight fever escape,
頭の中刻む甘いメモリ 戯れる
etching a sweet memory inside my head, playing around.
Slowly flowingで
Slowly flowing,
愛してるも通り越して
moving beyond even "I love you",
違う者同士こうして
different people, like this,
年老いるまでは笑っていたいね
I want us to keep laughing until we grow old.
君がいなきゃlonely lonely day
Without you, it's a lonely, lonely day.
夢の中 Fall asleep in bed
Falling asleep in bed inside a dream,
起こすから morning callで
I'll wake you up with a morning call.
I'll protect you from nightmares, Baby
重ねた手はね 離さないでいて
Please don't let go of our joined hands,
ごめん これ そばに居たいだけだね
sorry, I guess I just want to be by your side.
抱えた想いは お互い様でしょ
The feelings we hold are mutual, right?
ほら おあいこでしょ
See, we're even, aren't we?
すれ違い 間違いもあるし
There are misunderstandings and mistakes too,
筋書き通り行かない打診
and things don't go according to the script.
悲しみだって半分こにしよう
Let's share even our sadness in half,
別れじゃない希望
a hope that is not a farewell.
独りよがりにならないように
So as not to become self-centered,
いつも
always...
君がいなきゃ今もどこかで
Without you, even now, somewhere,
動けないままの僕で
with me being unable to move,
ありがとうを伝えたいのです
I want to tell you "thank you."
たいのです
...I want to say thank you.
これからは僕が支えてくって
From now on, I'll support you...
呆れてしまうくらいにね
...even if you find me annoying.
愛が増していく day by day
My love grows day by day.
面と向かうとどうしても
No matter what, when we face each other...
素直になれないな、ごめんね
I can't be honest. I'm sorry.
戯れ合う slowly, slowly flow で
Playfully drifting in a slowly, slowly flow...
愛してるも通り越して
Going far beyond even "I love you"...
似た者同士こうして
...two of a kind, just like this...
年老いるまでは笑っていたいね
...I want to laugh together like this until we grow old.
君がいなきゃ lonely, lonely day
Without you, it's a lonely, lonely day.
夢の中 fall asleep in bed
In my dreams, falling asleep in bed.
起こすから morning call で
I'll wake you up with a morning call.
I'll protect you from nightmares, Baby
ありがとうございました
Thank you very much!
はい、それではですね、皆さん
Alright, everyone...
歌、聴いていただきまして、本当にありがとうございました
Thank you so much for listening to my song!
はぁ、こんなに...
Phew, like this...
歌わせていただいたんですけども、バラード
I was allowed to sing... a ballad.
なかなか3Dライブでやらないので
I don't really sing them during 3D lives, so...
すごく緊張しました
...I was extremely nervous.
どうだったでしょうか？
How was it?
あ、めっちゃ、めっちゃ拍手と「めっちゃいい」ってやつが見える！
Oh, I can see so much applause and comments saying "so good"!
ありがとうございます！
Thank you so much!
そして、ここで、皆さんお待ちかねの
And now, here is the moment you've all been waiting for...
あの告知を挟ませていただければと思います！
...I would like to make that announcement!
それでは元気にいきます！
Alright, let's announce it with energy!
それでは、ドン！
Here we go, bam!
風真いろは、2025誕生日記念グッズ出ます！イェーイ！
Kazama Iroha 2025 Birthday Celebration merchandise is released! Yay!
ビジュアルが大変よろしい！
The visual looks absolutely wonderful!
こちらのグッズが販売決定です！
These goods are officially on sale!
はい、というわけで、詳細を見ていきましょう、ドン！
Alright, let's take a look at the details. Bam!
はい、まず一つ目は、回転アクリルスタンド！
Alright, first up is the rotating acrylic stand!
イラストは、Nardack先生に描いていただきました！うわぁ！
The illustration was drawn by Nardack-sensei! Wow!
こちらですね、あの...
For this one, well...
こう、こういうことです！
It's like... like this!
あの、裏表になってるって言いたい、裏、裏表になってる！
I mean, it's double-sided! Double-sided!
そう、あの、カラーライズ衣装と、この新しい新衣装で裏表になってます！
Right, it's double-sided with the Colorize outfit and this new outfit!
クルクル回せるので、あの...
Since it spins around, you can...
ござるのこと回して遊んでください、よろしくお願いします！
...spin me around and play with it! Please check it out!
そして、次がこちら！
And next is this!
はい、温感湯呑み！
Yes, a temperature-sensitive tea cup!
これ、ついさっきサンプルが控え室に届いて試しました！
The sample just arrived in the dressing room a moment ago, and I tried it out!
あの、ちゃんと温かいのを入れると、ふわってですね...
If you pour hot liquid in, it gently...
ちゃんとぽこべぇが浮き出て、ござるが打ち合わせとかね、
...reveals Pokobe! While I was in meetings or...
リハやってる間に湯が冷めきってちゃんと緑に戻っておりました！
...rehearsals, the hot water cooled down and it went back to green!
こちらもすごく可愛くて、お寿司屋さんとかにあるサイズなのかな？
This is also super cute! Is it the size of a tea cup you find at sushi restaurants?
結構大きめのちゃんとした湯呑みです、ぜひね、使ってもらえたら嬉しいです！
It's quite a large, proper tea cup, so I'd love for you to use it!
はい、そして次がこちら！
Alright, next up is this!
はい、風真いろは、新...
Yes, Kazama Iroha's new...
こちら、ポップダンス衣装って名前なんですけど、のぬいぐるみです！
...well, it's called the Pop Dance outfit—this is the plushie!
ぜひお迎えしてほしいな！
I really hope you'll take one home!
ござるさんのぬいぐるみです！みんな遊んでくれ！
It's a Gozaru-san plushie! Please play with it, everyone!
っていうことで、このツインテールのね、新衣装、なんとぬいぐるみになりました！
So, this twin-tailed new outfit has actually become a plushie!
あの、手持ちじゃなくて、こ、こういうタイプだったかな？と思うので、
It's not a hand-held strap type, but more of a sitting type, I believe.
ぜひね、みんなのおうちに飾ってもらえたら嬉しいです！
So I'd be happy if you displayed it in your room!
そして次がこちら！
And next is this!
はい、なんとござるのこれ！これとお揃いのこれがでます！
Yes, actually, this one that I'm wearing! An identical matching one is coming out!
じ、ちょっと待ってね、言い直していい？
W-Wait a moment, can I say that again?
これとお揃いのネックレスが出ます！
A necklace identical to this one is coming out!
はい！
Yes!
普段ね、アクセサリーとか付けない、体質、ね、付けないよっていう方も、ま、よかったら、
Even if you don't usually wear accessories or can't wear them, if you'd like...
こちらね、あの、さっきのぬいぐるみに結んで、一緒にセットにして飾っていただいたりとか、
...you can wrap it around the plushie and display them together as a set,
イベントのときに付けてきてもらえたら嬉しいです！
or wear it when you come to events!
おしゃれです！ござると一緒にお揃いに、よかったらしましょう！
It's very stylish! Let's wear matching necklaces together!
というわけで、そして、フルセットがこんな感じ？
And so, the full set looks like this!
うわぁ！なんか爽やかですね！
Wow! It feels so refreshing!
そう、ライブタイトルの通り「リバーシブル」なんでね、色々ちょっと、反転反転が付いてたりします！
Right, just like the live's title "Reversible," various things are reversed!
そして、購入特典はこちら！
And here is the purchase bonus!
「この戦争を終わらせにきました」
"I have come to end this war."
今回はですね、グッズが2種類出るということで、数量限定はせずに、
This time, since we are releasing two main visual styles, instead of a limited quantity,
ちょっと変わった特典にしてみました！
...we decided to offer a slightly unique bonus!
こちらは、裏表のタロットカードが付いてきます！
This comes with a double-sided tarot card!
片面にはね、風真の、えっと、複製サインとメッセージが入っております！
One side features my duplicated signature and message!
こちらもね、こう裏表で...
This one is also double-sided...
楽しんでもらえたら嬉しいです。
I'd be happy if you enjoy it.
数量限定とかではないので ゆっくり購入していただければと思います。
It's not limited in quantity, so please take your time to purchase.
販売開始時間がこの後21時なんですけど ちょっと生配信の都合上 延びる可能性のほうが今大なので
Sales start at 21:00, but because the live stream will likely run over,
生配信中に皆さん 買いに行ってください。
please go and buy them during the stream!
あ、でも 数量限定とかはないので 安心してください。
But don't worry, they aren't limited in quantity.
はい。そしてフルセットの特典 もう1つあります！こちらです。
Yes. And there's one more full-set bonus! Here it is.
はい！みんな大好きホロカのカードが1枚付いてきます！
Yes! It comes with one Hololive Official Card Game card!
はい 皆さん よかったらお手に取って ホロカ勢の皆さんは使ってくださいね。
Please get your hands on it, and Hololive Card Game players, please use it!
遊び方やカードの詳細情報は ホロライブオフィシャルカードゲームの公式ホームページにてご確認ください！
For how to play and card details, please check the official Hololive Card Game website!
よし！今 台本めっちゃ見た。言えなかったらやばいと思って。
Alright! I was staring at the script just now, thinking it'd be bad if I messed up.
そしてこちら、同封させていただくカードは日本語版のみとなっておりますので、ご了承ください。
Please note that the included card is only available in the Japanese version.
はい。
Yes.
カートオープンですが、100万人記念グッズと誕生日記念グッズ両方同時なので、よろしくお願いします。生配信押しちゃってごめんね。
The cart will open for both the 1 Million Subs and Birthday Goods at the same time. Sorry for delaying the stream.
ホロメンも、ホロメンも配信を押し、すみません！
To the other Holomembers whose streams I delayed, I'm so sorry!
はい。というわけで、ちょっとお水飲みます。
Alright. With that, I'll drink some water.
はい。というわけで、
Okay. So,
あと最後のお知らせとしまして、この後、本編終了次第、ちょっとまた時間がね、確定、15分からか20分からか、どっちかになると思うんですけど、
as the final announcement, once this main stream ends—the exact time isn't set, but probably starting in 15 or 20 minutes—
風真いろはのメンバーシップ限定のアンコールライブがございますので、
there will be an encore live stream exclusive to Kazama Iroha members!
みんなが見たかったあの曲やこの曲を歌ったり踊ったりしますので、よかったら見に来てください！
I'll sing and dance to the songs you've all wanted to see, so please come watch!
よろしくお願いします。メンバーシップギフトとか、今日から入ってくださった隊士さんもありがとうございます！
Thank you. And thank you to those who gifted memberships and the recruits who joined today!
はい。そしてなんと残念なことに、次の曲が、皆さん、このライブ最後の曲となります。
And unfortunately, everyone, the next song will be the final song of this live stream.
皆さん、もう最後は何を歌うか、ある程度予想されている方も多いかと思いますが、改めまして、
I'm sure many of you have already guessed what the final song will be, but once again,
この度は、風真いろは生誕ライブ2025、お越しくださいまして、本当にありがとうございました！
thank you so much for coming to Kazama Iroha Birthday Live 2025!
そして、制作のために一生懸命頑張ってくださったスタッフさんや、ダンスの先生やマネージャーさん、クリエイターの皆さんも、本当にありがとうございました。
I also want to thank the staff, dance instructors, managers, and creators who worked so hard on this production.
正直、色々あった昨年の年末から、
Honestly, after everything that happened at the end of last year,
ここまで声が戻ってライブができるっていうことが、ほぼ奇跡。
it's almost a miracle that my voice recovered enough to do a live stream.
なんなら、もう半分諦めかけていたんですけども、
To tell the truth, I had almost half given up,
スタッフの皆さんや、ファンの隊士さんたちがすごい支えてくださって、いろんな方に支えられて、本日実施することができました。本当にありがとうございます。
but with the support of the staff and all my recruits, I was able to hold this today. Thank you so much.
正直、まだ本調子じゃない部分が多いのは事実です。
Frankly, it's true that I'm still not in perfect shape.
だけど、今日少しでもこのライブを見て、たくさんの人に元気が、1人でも多く届いていればなと思っております。
But I hope that by watching this live stream today, even just one more person was able to receive some energy.
これからもリハビリしながらですが、精一杯がんばってまいりますので、皆さん、これからもよろしくお願いします！
I will continue to do my best while undergoing rehabilitation, so everyone, please continue to support me!
はい。
Yes.
というわけで、最後の曲にふさわしいこの曲、
So, this song, which is fitting for the final song,
皆さん、最後に聞いてください。風真いろは 新オリ曲、「君にしか読めない手紙」。
everyone, please listen to it as the finale. Kazama Iroha's new original song, "A Letter Only You Can Read."
ありがとうを書くとしたら 毎日になっちゃうくらい
If I were to write down "thank you," it would be every single day,
重すぎる私の想いは 最後に伝えるね
my feelings, which are too heavy, I'll tell you at the very end.
君にしか読めない手紙
[Song: A Letter Only You Can Read]
拝啓 私を 形作った君へ
Dear you, who shaped who I am,
相も変わらず言葉を 届け続けています
I'm still sending you words, just as always.
拝啓 未来で 私待ってる君へ
Dear you, who is waiting for me in the future,
響く音に憂いなど なくお過ごしでしょうか
are you doing well without any grief in the echoing sounds?
不安が無い日なんて 多分無かったけど
There probably wasn't a day without anxiety, but
私の言葉 君の言葉 重なって笑えたんだ
my words and your words overlapped, and we were able to laugh.
ありがとうを書くとしたら 毎日になっちゃうくらい
If I were to write down "thank you," it would be every single day,
重すぎる...
too heavy...
私の想いは
My feelings...
最後に伝えるね
I'll tell you at the very end.
君がいる それだけでさ
Just because you are here,
理由になるなんて奇跡
it becomes a reason—what a miracle!
ありがとう 足りないの 誤魔化すよ
"Thank you" isn't enough, so I'll cover it up...
愛してる
...with "I love you"!
魔法石のブレスレット
A bracelet of magic stones,
シロツメクサの女王様
and the white clover queen.
プラスチックだらけの宝石箱で
With a jewelry box full of plastic toys,
ずっと遊べるよ君と
I can go on playing with you forever.
思い出の欠片たち
The fragments of memories...
溢れるこの場所で
In this place overflowing with them,
私の言葉 君の言葉
your words and my words...
重ねて笑ってたい
I want to bring them together and laugh.
忘れられる世界で今
In a world where everything gets forgotten,
私が選んだ生き方
this is the way of life I chose.
手紙をさ 書いたからさ
You see, I wrote you a letter...
この音に乗せて
and set it to this melody.
ありがとう 書くとしたら
If I were to write "thank you,"
毎日になっちゃうくらい
I would end up writing it every single day.
重すぎる私の想いは
My feelings, which are far too heavy,
最後に伝えるね
I will tell you at the very end.
君がいる それだけでさ
Just because you are here,
理由になるなんて奇跡
it becomes a reason—what a miracle!
ありがとう 足りないの 誤魔化すよ
"Thank you" isn't enough, so I'll cover it up...
愛してる
...with "I love you"!
ありがとうございました！
Thank you very much!
風真いろは
[Kazama Iroha]
100万人記念
[1 Million Subscriber Celebration]
7月1日
[July 1st]
MV公開
[MV Release]
「君にしか読めない手紙」
7月1日 MV公開
["A Letter Only You Can Read"
July 1st MV Release]
Reversible
風真いろは 生誕LIVE 2025
[Reversible
Kazama Iroha Birthday LIVE 2025]